易考范文三十三
As can be seen in the picture,
a college student parks his car outside the campus.
He is equipped with a notebook computer,
a digital camera, an MP3 and dressed
in clothes of famous brand. Ironically,
on the wall behind him there is a slogan
advocating independence and thrift
among college students.
This picture conveys a clear message that
college students ought to maintain a rational attitude
toward consumption and a positive
outlook on life and studies.
This phenomenon, in reality, is not uncommon.
As a member of a highly consumption-oriented society,
young people are increasingly aware of new products
and famous brands. However, they are liable
to buy things impulsively and less sensibly
than the market as a whole. On the other hand,
young people are heavily dependent on their parents,
who usually exert themselves to satisfy
the demands of their children,
because most Chinese families have only one child
due to the one-child policy. In addition,
the fact that college students channel
too much energy and time into shopping
and keeping up with the Joneses makes it unlikely
for them to concentrate on their study,
which is the major task for them as students.
Since independence, diligence and thrift
are virtues many college students lack,
it is vital that families, society as well as schools
guide them in terms of consumption
and impress on them the importance of
industry and self-support.